<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rogue Photon</title>
    <link>https://roguephoton.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rogue Photon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:30:25 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roguephoton.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Combat Update</title>
      <link>https://roguephoton.com/posts/combat-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:30:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roguephoton.com/posts/combat-update/</guid>
      
      <description>Base functionality I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that the combat system is now functional.
Units can deal damage Units can take damage In other words: a die may die&amp;hellip; [I&amp;rsquo;ll let myself out] Your browser does not support the video tag. Your browser does not support the video tag. No health bars or visual effects yet just destroying the unit after it dies. Left the blue path indicators and white placeholder effect for attacks (to at least see the attack rate).</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathfinding Update</title>
      <link>https://roguephoton.com/posts/pathfinding-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 21:22:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roguephoton.com/posts/pathfinding-update/</guid>
      
      <description>Core RTS features I&amp;rsquo;m sharing progress related to most essential RTS features:
Unit selection Unit movement Physics interaction Your browser does not support the video tag. As shown in the video - the units can choose the correct path to their destination.
Challanges Already at this stage due to the unique idea of relying on physics for unit movement I had to solve some issues:
[problem] The units are terribly slow if using only torque for movement.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die Commander Introductions</title>
      <link>https://roguephoton.com/posts/die-commander/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 18:09:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roguephoton.com/posts/die-commander/</guid>
      
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Rogue Photon – Solo Game Developer Welcome to my devlog! I&amp;rsquo;m a self-taught developer/physicist/musician working on a number of projects. Recently I&amp;rsquo;m building [Die Commander] (&amp;ldquo;Die&amp;rdquo; as a singular of dice, working title), a physics-based RTS where dice aren&amp;rsquo;t just tools – they&amp;rsquo;re your units.
In this blog I will write updates about the game&amp;rsquo;s development, from prototype to (hopefully) release. Expect posts about:
Core features of most RTS games adjusted to my needs Behind-the-scenes struggles Requests for help in the decision making The Core Mechanic: Dice as Units At the heart of [Die Commander] lies a simple but deadly premise: your units are dice, and their combat relies entirely on physics-based rolls.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
